S M SAMFFR

Data Specialist



SUMMARY

Software Engineer with around 2 years of experience in building user interactive applications, possess hands-on experience in solving syntactical challenges and scalability problems for different domains. Inclined towards the field of data engineering with a desire to expand my skill sets.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Specialist

Futurense Technologies 12/2022 - Ongoing Bangalore, Karnataka Tools Used: SQL, Python, Git, AWS Cloud, Hive, Hadoop

- Implemented SQL reporting on employee management system to gain insights on building various reporting formats
- · Gained an overview of the whole process of **Data Engineering**
- Worked on core services in Azure Cloud under security, compute, storage, database, etc

Automation Engineer

Valenta Al 01/2020 - 11/2020 Bangalore, Karnataka

Tools Used: (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, OneReach.ai, Dialog Flow)

- Worked on project like creating interactive chatbot for Unicomer Group, have also deployed chatbot in various form of channels (WhatsApp, RWC, Facebook, etc)
- Enhanced several features that reduced the manual intervention by automating the process which helped to minimize the error rate by
- Worked on maintaining a database containing feedback, conversations, and interests of individuals

PROJECTS

HealthCare Management

06/2020 - 07/2020 Bangalore, Karnataka

Tools: Python, MySQL

Developed **15+ stored routines** with features such as obtaining pharmacy information for particular medications, determining the count of patients treated for specific diseases in a given city and year, etc

- Utilized SQL Joins, Aggregate Functions, and Window Functions to extract meaningful insights from the data
- Constructed 3 triggers to monitor and store the date and time of when a new city or state is added to the database, and to track all transactions that involve updating inventory

PlayerTracker: Building a Comprehensive Database for Tracking Player

09/2022 - 10/2022 Bangalore, Karnataka

A **Python interface** developed for users where they can provide their time played every day to track the usage of the package taken.

- $\,\cdot\,$ Created a python-interface, with a menu-driven approach to automate the process of admin users
- Collected and stored the duration using <code>MySQL</code> database and built <code>3</code> triggers to stream line the process of inserting data, and trigger to make decision on the subscription status
- Worked on Visualization palette to show the usage of the package and total hours played by the user using **Matplotlib**

EDUCATION

B. Tech - CSE

PRESIDENCY UNIVERSITY, BENGALURU

08/2018 - 07/2022

GPA 7.77 / 10

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python

MySQL

••••

TECHNOLOGY SKILL SETS

Pandas

PySpark

NumPy

Hadoop

Hive

Unix Shell Scripting

Git

AWS

CERTIFICATION

Supervised Learning with scikit-learn Bootcamp, July 2020

Applied Plotting, Charting & Data Representation in Python Coursera, August 2021

ACHIEVEMENTS

1st Prize - Photography Competition Secured 1st prize for On The Spot photography in an inter-college photography competition

INTERESTS

Editing, Traveling, Badminton